Preliminary Inventory to the Leland Lasell Rounds Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Leland Lasell Rounds Papers
1916-1962
71018
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Correspondence, memoranda, orders, printed matter, and photographs, relating to French and American aerial operations in World War I, and to Allied intelligence operations in North Africa preceding Allied landings in 1942. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Rounds, Leland Lasell, 1891-
Access
Collection open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1971.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
France. Armée. Service aéronautique. Escadrille n. 112..; United States. Army. American Expeditionary Forces.; United States. Office of Strategic Services.; France.; Secret service--United States.; United States--Armed Forces.; World War, 1914-1918--Aerial operations.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Africa, North.; World War, 1939-1945--Secret service.; World War, 1939-1945.
- World War I (Box 1)
  - Lafayette Flying Corps and Escadrille. Miscellaneous publications, brochures, photographs, correspondence and souvenirs
  - France. Armee. Miscellaneous forms, orders, notes
  - French air maps. Area covered by the escadrilles of the Lafayette Flying Corps
  - James Norman Hall. Letters to his friend Rounds, articles, and photographs
  - United States. Army. Miscellaneous orders, notes, etc.
  - Miscellaneous articles from American newspapers, 1917-1918
- World War II
  - Miscellaneous letters relating to intelligence work in North Africa
  - Landings on North Africa on November 1942. Miscellaneous papers, photographs, notes, orders, circa 1942
  - Letters and notes concerning certain French personalities
  - Intelligence notes, Oran, Vichy, 1941
  - Newspaper and magazine articles, 1941-1943
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, Algeria, 1943-1944
  - Intelligence data regarding communist collaboration with Nazi Germany
  - We Accuse, by Jerry King (and others), 1940. Book regarding certain activities of the communists in the Maritime Union
- Declassified U.S. government records, 1942-1943
  - 2018 release of declassified records, 1942-1943 (Reading room workstation)